Inventory of the María Haydée Terán letters
Hoover Institution Archives
María Haydée Terán letters
1969-1970
2010C53
Terán, María Haydée
1 manuscript box (0.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Letters from María Haydée Terán to Carlos Fonseca Amador, founder of the Frente Sandinista de Liberación Nacional in Nicaragua, largely relating to personal matters. Includes a few letters by Carlos Fonseca Amador.
Administrative Information
Access
Closed. Microfilm use copy available.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2010.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Forms of Material Available
Microfilm use copy available
Biographical/Historical Note
Wife of Carlos Fonseca Amador.
Scope and Content of Collection
Letters from María Haydée Terán to Carlos Fonseca Amador, founder of the Frente Sandinista de Liberación Nacional in Nicaragua, largely relating to personal matters. Includes a few letters by Carlos Fonseca Amador.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Nicaragua--Politics and government.; Frente Sandinista de Liberación Nacional.; Fonseca Amador, Carlos.
Collection Contents
- Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  Contains letters
  Arranged by name of sender, all on reel number 1.
  - From María Haydée Terán to Carlos Fonseca Amador, 1969-1970
    - 1969 January 21 (Folder 1: 1)
    - 1970 March 1 (Folder 1: 2)
    - 1970 March 12 (Folder 1: 3)
    - 1970 April 21 (Folder 1: 4)
    - 1970 April 28 (Folder 1: 5)
    - 1970 May 26 (Folder 1: 6)
    - 1970 May 28 (Folder 1: 7)
    - 1970 June 7 (Folder 1: 8)
    - 1970 June 15 (Folder 1: 9)
    - 1970 July 6 (Folder 1: 10)
    - 1970 July 9 (Folder 1: 11)
    - 1970 July 15 (Folder 1: 12)
    - 1970 July 17 (Folder 1: 13)
    - 1970 July 25 (Folder 1: 14)
    - 1970 July 29 (Folder 1: 15)
    - 1970 July 30 (Folder 1: 16)
    - 1970 August 2 (Folder 1: 17)
    - 1970 August 7 (Folder 1: 18)
    - 1970 August 12 (Folder 1: 19)
    - 1970 August 17 (Folder 1: 20)
    - 1970 August 19 (Folder 1: 21)
    - 1970 September 1 (missing page 6) (Folder 1: 22)
    - 1970 September 3 (Folder 1: 23)
  - From Carlos Fonseca Amador to Abdenago "Nago" Hernández Cascante and Graciella "Chelita" Sancho Colombari, 1970 May 18 (Folder 1: 24)
  - From Carlos Fonseca Amador to Abdenago "Nago" Hernández Cascante, 1970 September 12 (Folder 1: 25)
  - From Carlos Fonseca Amador to Graciella "Chelita" Sancho Colombari, 1970 September 15 (Folder 1: 26)
- Writing, 1970 (Box 1)
  Contains instructions
  - Instructions written by Carlos Fonseca Amador on how to communicate with journalists, 1970 (Folder 1: 27)